<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<translations>
  <LiveCurious PreviewUrl="~/livecurious">
    <col1block2Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col1block2Title>
    <col1block2Subtitle><![CDATA[The (dead) Elephant in the Room]]></col1block2Subtitle>
    <col1block2Description><![CDATA[When faced with five tons of dead Jumbo, a zoo typically chooses the most common means of disposal. But what are the options?]]></col1block2Description>
    <col1block3Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col1block3Title>
    <col1block3Subtitle><![CDATA[Jawsbreaker]]></col1block3Subtitle>
    <col1block3Description><![CDATA[Although you are more likely to be hit by lightning than attacked by Jaws… is it possible to scare off a shark?]]></col1block3Description>
    <col1block4Title><![CDATA[IF NOT NOW THEN WHEN?]]></col1block4Title>
    <col1block5Title><![CDATA[EVERYTHING DESERVES A ... ?]]></col1block5Title>
    <col1block5Description><![CDATA[Such a simple word that unlocks many doors.]]></col1block5Description>
    <col1block7Title><![CDATA[ASK]]></col1block7Title>
    <col1block7Subtitle><![CDATA[LIVE: spend one's life in a particular way or under particular circumstances. CURIOUS: eager to know or learn something.]]></col1block7Subtitle>
    <col2block1Title><![CDATA[IGNORANCE IS BORING]]></col2block1Title>
    <col2block1Description><![CDATA[Is it possible to know the truth without challenging it first]]></col2block1Description>
    <col2block2Title><![CDATA[TWITTER]]></col2block2Title>
    <col2block2Subtitle><![CDATA[Look at our latest feed.]]></col2block2Subtitle>
    <col2block2Description><![CDATA[<a href="http://twitter.com/live_curious/" target="_blank">Follow us on Twitter</a>]]></col2block2Description>
    <col2block3Title><![CDATA[SO MANY QUESTIONS]]></col2block3Title>
    <col2block3Subtitle><![CDATA[Discover answers to questions you might not yet even have considered]]></col2block3Subtitle>
    <col2block3Description><![CDATA[Ask again]]></col2block3Description>
    <col2block4Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col2block4Title>
    <col2block4Subtitle><![CDATA[Fired Up]]></col2block4Subtitle>
    <col2block4Desciption><![CDATA[What goes up must come down… so is it possible to be killed by a bullet shot straight up into the air?]]></col2block4Desciption>
    <col2block5Title><![CDATA[IF NOT NOW THEN WHEN?]]></col2block5Title>
    <col2block6Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col2block6Title>
    <col2block6Subtitle><![CDATA[Shock and Awe]]></col2block6Subtitle>
    <col2block6Description><![CDATA[Why does static electricity build on televisions, computer monitors and human hair?]]></col2block6Description>
    <col2block7Title><![CDATA[PLAY]]></col2block7Title>
    <col2block7Subtitle><![CDATA[Most of humanity stays in their comfort zone. Don't be "most". <strong>Play</strong> outside.]]></col2block7Subtitle>
    <col3block1Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col3block1Title>
    <col3block1Subtitle><![CDATA[Farewell My Sun]]></col3block1Subtitle>
    <col3block1Description><![CDATA[According to current estimates the sun will be around for at least another five billion years. But what if it were to suddenly disappear?]]></col3block1Description>
    <col3block2Title><![CDATA[IF (PROMO)]]></col3block2Title>
    <col3block2Subtitle><![CDATA[More]]></col3block2Subtitle>
    <col3block2Description><![CDATA[If you are, you breath. If you breath, you talk. If you talk, you ask. If you ask, you think. If you think, you search. If you search, you experience. If you experience, you learn. If you learn, you grow. If you grow, you wish. If you wish, you find. And if you find… you doubt. If you doubt, you question. If you question, you understand. If you understand, you know. And if you know, you want to know more. And if you want to know more, you are… alive.]]></col3block2Description>
    <col3block3Title><![CDATA[THE MORE WE KNOW]]></col3block3Title>
    <col3block3Subtitle><![CDATA[The more we don't know.]]></col3block3Subtitle>
    <col3block3Description><![CDATA[The more we know we don't know]]></col3block3Description>
    <col3block4Title><![CDATA[FIND US ON FACEBOOK]]></col3block4Title>
    <col3block4Subtitle><![CDATA[Everything deserves a WHY]]></col3block4Subtitle>
    <col3block4Description><![CDATA[<a href="?url=http://www.facebook.com/apps/application.php?id=261530915451" target="_blank">Check out our Profile!</a>]]></col3block4Description>
    <col3block5Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col3block5Title>
    <col3block5Subtitle><![CDATA[A comet tale]]></col3block5Subtitle>
    <col3block5Description><![CDATA[We are not alone in the universe. There is a massive amount of celestial activity constantly occurring throughout the cosmos, so what would happen if the Earth were to pass through the tail of a comet?]]></col3block5Description>
    <col3block6Title><![CDATA[IF NOT NOW THEN WHEN?]]></col3block6Title>
    <col3block7Title><![CDATA[WATCH]]></col3block7Title>
    <col3block7Subtitle><![CDATA[Love facts. Depend on information. Watch a channel that makes curiosity a way of life.]]></col3block7Subtitle>
    <col4block1Title><![CDATA[HOW CURIOUS ARE YOU?]]></col4block1Title>
    <col4block1Subtitle><![CDATA[Put your knowledge to the test]]></col4block1Subtitle>
    <col4block1Description><![CDATA[<a href="?url=http://apps.facebook.com/livecurious/?_fb_q=1" target="_blank">Play our Live Curious game</a> and compare your status on Facebook.]]></col4block1Description>
    <col4block2Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col4block2Title>
    <col4block2Subtitle><![CDATA[Baby Steps]]></col4block2Subtitle>
    <col4block2Description><![CDATA[If human adults are so clearly superior when compared to other animals, why are human babies so inferior?]]></col4block2Description>
    <col4block3Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col4block3Title>
    <col4block3Subtitle><![CDATA[Thunder Bolts and Lightning, Very Very Frightening]]></col4block3Subtitle>
    <col4block3Description><![CDATA[If there is no smoke without fire, can there be lightning without thunder?]]></col4block3Description>
    <col4block4Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col4block4Title>
    <col4block4Subtitle><![CDATA[Tickle Me, Myself and I]]></col4block4Subtitle>
    <col4block4Description><![CDATA[As well as being fun, the humble tickle has been used as a form of torture… but have you ever tried to tickle yourself?]]></col4block4Description>
    <col4block5Title><![CDATA[IF NOT NOW THEN WHEN?]]></col4block5Title>
    <col4block6Title><![CDATA[ASK THE EXPERT]]></col4block6Title>
    <col4block6Subtitle><![CDATA[Return to Sender]]></col4block6Subtitle>
    <col4block6Description><![CDATA[The boomerang is a type of throwing stick most closely associated with Australian aborigines. What makes a boomerang return to the person who threw it?]]></col4block6Description>
    <col4block7Title><![CDATA[COMMUNICATE]]></col4block7Title>
    <col4block7Subtitle><![CDATA[Where knowledge ends, curiosity begins.]]></col4block7Subtitle>
    <col1block2VideoId><![CDATA[62883117001]]></col1block2VideoId>
    <col1block3VideoId><![CDATA[62883108001]]></col1block3VideoId>
    <col1block5VideoId><![CDATA[60310498001]]></col1block5VideoId>
    <col2block4VideoId><![CDATA[62878887001]]></col2block4VideoId>
    <col2block6VideoId><![CDATA[62880236001]]></col2block6VideoId>
    <col3block1VideoId><![CDATA[62882908001]]></col3block1VideoId>
    <col3block2VideoId><![CDATA[60310486001]]></col3block2VideoId>
    <col3block5VideoId><![CDATA[62874518001]]></col3block5VideoId>
    <col4block2VideoId><![CDATA[62883115001]]></col4block2VideoId>
    <col4block3VideoId><![CDATA[62883105001]]></col4block3VideoId>
    <col4block4VideoId><![CDATA[62880234001]]></col4block4VideoId>
    <col4block6VideoId><![CDATA[62880240001]]></col4block6VideoId>
    <twitterUserame><![CDATA[live_curious]]></twitterUserame>
    <twitterNumTweets><![CDATA[5]]></twitterNumTweets>
    <twitterLoadingText><![CDATA[Loading tweets…]]></twitterLoadingText>
    <facebookProfileId><![CDATA[261530915451]]></facebookProfileId>
  </LiveCurious>
  <GreatMigrations>
    <title><![CDATA[Great Migrations]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[Our romantic vision of animal migrations is all wrong: they are not leisurely strolls, swims and soars. They are tortuous marathons borne of suffering, starvation and desperation. Every migrant wages a death-defying journey, facing countless obstacles in the name of self-preservation or the survival of the species. The risks are enormous and the energetic costs immense but somehow these bold creatures know the only thing worse than leaving, is staying put.]]></description>
    <subTitle><![CDATA[MOVE AS MILLIONS. SURVIVE AS ONE.]]></subTitle>
    <commingSoon><![CDATA[COMING SOON]]></commingSoon>
    <videoId><![CDATA[596218015001]]></videoId>
    <blogExcerpts><![CDATA[PRODUCTION DIARY]]></blogExcerpts>
    <beMainTitle><![CDATA[Excerpts<br />from Behind the Camera]]></beMainTitle>
    <bePrevious><![CDATA[previous]]></bePrevious>
    <beNext><![CDATA[next]]></beNext>
    <be1Title><![CDATA[CHEETAH CUBS UNDER THE 4X4]]></be1Title>
    <be1Description><![CDATA[It was day 13 with the mother cheetah and her three hungry cubs.  She seemed to be more determined today, considering her last 4 days of hunting had been unsuccessful.  I was sitting in my 4x4 filming vehicle with my camera locked - loaded & ready for the action.  With her three cubs trailing her like an articulated extension of her own impressive tail, she began to stalk closer and closer to a group of gazelles, and closer and closer to my filming vehicle.  "Brilliant..." I thought - "If she keeps creeping closer to my lens I'm going to get an amazing shot of her taking down one of those gazelles".   As she continued her stalk it became apparent that she was getting almost too close to my 4x4.... I was in trouble!]]></be1Description>
    <be2Title><![CDATA[AMAZON]]></be2Title>
    <be2Description><![CDATA[What I did find out during the 7-day wait, was that Peru is hot. Songbirds love landing on my blind, and as I baked in my glorified tent, I would soon find out that every day around 2PM the mud bank where I sat became a lizard highway. Making all kinds of noise, and causing me to look out the windows in fear of the jaguar, or anaconda, or caiman that might eat me… One of my favorite things about sitting quietly in the wilderness for the entire day is that you see and hear the most amazing things. The animals have no idea you are there and you can observe them dealing with every day life on their terms. I love my job. [John Benham]]]></be2Description>
    <be3Title><![CDATA[ARMY ANTS]]></be3Title>
    <be3Description><![CDATA[The forest was like an obstacle course…we scanned the forest floor for ants with our heads down to the ground, and blindly dodged hanging, spiky tree branches. We walked and walked and didn’t come across anything for miles <br /> <br />At one point, I was so delirious from the heat exhaustion and constantly bending over that I quickly raised my head and banged my head on what I thought was a branch.  I looked up and hear a loud buzzing in my ears.  The sound grew louder and I was soon surrounded by hundreds of bees.  They were all over me – in my ears, in my hair, and all over my body!  I had banged my head into a beehive! [Stephanie Atlas]]]></be3Description>
    <be4Title><![CDATA[WHALES]]></be4Title>
    <be4Description><![CDATA[Rick brought the “banana boat” from California— a bright yellow inflatable tandem kayak, which could be pedaled or paddled into the whales.  Now the whales hardly noticed our attempts to get a glimpse into their world.  This was a great turning point in our filming.  Well, great for everyone except maybe Kai and Mario who take turns navigating the kayak, pedaling as fast as swimming whales, sometimes for a solid half hour or more to bring Rick in close enough to get a shot.  But we are all relieved that we now have a much better chance of actually filming the whales that take so much time and effort to find.]]></be4Description>
    <be5Title><![CDATA[ALBATROSS]]></be5Title>
    <be5Description><![CDATA[As evening approached, we noticed more birds, mainly albatross, around our boat.  Anticipation grew at this sign of land ahead.  Sure enough, we could soon make out the black outline of small islands on the horizon.  They were veiled in thick fog, with impressive spires jutting out the top, and crowded with silhouettes of albatross circling above.   Due to the misty visibility, we were right next to land before we could see the colony we had come to film.  As promised, thousands of albatross covered the shores, tightly packed together on their mud nests.  ]]></be5Description>
    <be6Title><![CDATA[ZEBRAS]]></be6Title>
    <be6Description><![CDATA[4/09/09<br />Dear David,<br />First day with mail connectivity. Seems erratic. Not surprised. We’re a long way from anywhere. <br />So, glad I can drop you a mail. <br />All systems are working. We came in four or five days ago, vehicles are in place, fuel drums dropped in strategic places and exactly a day before we arrived the zebras started dribbling in. Seen about 4,000 so far and understand that there will be 15,000 plus this year... <br />This is a stunning place...Got into position to film moonrise with zebras tonight and suddenly clouds came over and blew my shot, but gave some relief to the 90 degree day. Unless it buckets now, we may have timed this well. <br />Issues so far are few...but one is that no one here has seen a lion in a while. Rabies seems to have taken its toll and wiped out the lions. New pride in, seen once, is from hell, so they run like demons...By contrast, I am getting to within 100 yards of the herds of zebras, and chipping away at that, so getting some pleasing material. Chopper work starts Monday...Should be stunning. <br />All the best<br />Dereck ]]></be6Description>
    <be7Title><![CDATA[MALI ELEPHANTS]]></be7Title>
    <be7Description><![CDATA[The clarity of the stars above was amazing.  The silence was music to our ears, broken only by a jackal, perhaps unsettled by our intrusion.  But then, about an hour after we lay down, an eerie sound woke us: elephant trunks periscoping, sucking in air through their trunks and filtering it for strange scents, our scents. We had made camp right in the middle of an elephant highway!  <br /><br />Disoriented in the darkness, senses heightened, I felt like the noise was right beside me, the trunks about to touch my face (which was now frozen like the terrified painted figure in ‘The Scream’).  [James Byrne]]]></be7Description>
    <be8Title><![CDATA[MONARCH BUTTERFLY]]></be8Title>
    <be8Description><![CDATA[At around 10 AM, sunlight beamed through the trees and suddenly there was a burst from up above.  A tree covered by monarchs about 50 feet high exploded into a waterfall of butterflies.  What an incredible spectacle!  I had seen other monarch films and knew the sight was elegant, but I had no idea it would be this magnificent!  It looked like bursts of confetti cascading down to the ground.  One after another the trees were exploding…[Stephanie Atlas]]]></be8Description>
    <be9Title><![CDATA[PRONGHORN DIARY]]></be9Title>
    <be9Description><![CDATA[Joe and I are afraid to breath as the pronghorn move nervously toward the river for the next half hour.  Finally, they approach our cameras, but we can't tell if they've triggered them, or nor.  After nervous moments milling around, the pronghorn enter the water and much to our surprise, they're lead by a fawn.  Within moments they've crossed the river and passed out of sight.  Joe and I try to walk calmly to our cameras to check them, but about halfway there we can't resist the urge to break into a run. [Shane Moore]]]></be9Description>
    <be10Title><![CDATA[KOB]]></be10Title>
    <be10Description><![CDATA[Our shoot was only two weeks long but it was a year in the making.  Bob Poole, the cameraman, and I had scouted southern Sudan in early 2008. We returned to the US full of enthusiasm for the story – the migration of white-eared kob is one of the least known, and least filmed, large mammal migrations in the world.  Because of decades of civil war in Sudan, we would be the first crew to film the kob on the ground in almost thirty years.  [James Byrne]]]></be10Description>
    <be11Title><![CDATA[WHALESHARKS]]></be11Title>
    <be11Description><![CDATA[Right then, the swarm parts, and an enormous 20 foot long shark emerges from the fish.  Our true quarry… this is a great sign for the night.  He too is inquisitive… perhaps killing time playing with me and my camera… waiting for the moment when the fish erupt, and spawn fills the ocean.  That is why he is here, having traveled hundreds of mile for this exact event… and a meal of protein rich spawn.  That is why we are here. That is why everything is here.  [Andy Mitchell]]]></be11Description>
    <blogExcerptsTitle><![CDATA[get a preview behind the scenes with excerpts from the Great Migrations production diary]]></blogExcerptsTitle>
  </GreatMigrations>
  <POD></POD>
</translations>