<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<translations>
  <Common>
		<TitlePrefix><![CDATA[Neurocare Association - ]]></TitlePrefix>
    <Title><![CDATA[Neurocare Association - Join us - for life!]]></Title>
		<RightHead1><![CDATA[Paying homage]]></RightHead1>
		<RightContent1>
			<![CDATA[
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Exercitiu-de-admiratie2.jpg" class="Feature" />
			<p>Every time I come home I ring the doorbell just once, thinking that maybe my son is asleep; but most of the times I hear him calling:
			<i>Bibi</i> (that's his nanny)<i>, mommy's home! I'll get the truck!</i> When I come in, he welcomes me as he's riding his toy-truck and
			starts to tell me quickly, skipping words...
			<a href="##app_root##/cazuri/un-alt-fel-de-exercitiu-de-admiratie.aspx">read more</a></p>
			]]>
		</RightContent1>
		<RightHead2><![CDATA[Redirect 2% of your taxes to Asociatia Neurocare]]></RightHead2>
		<RightContent2>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>If wages is your exclusive income, fill in the 230 form.
			<a href="##app_root##/doneaza.aspx#formular230" runat="server">details...</a></p>
			<div class="DownloadItem">
				<a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular230_2015_Neurocare.pdf" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 230', 'Coloana din dreapta']);" target="_blank">
					<img src="##app_root##/App/Images/PdfIcon.png" alt="Pdf Icon" /></a>
				<a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular230_2015_Neurocare.pdf" class="Text" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 230', 'Coloana din dreapta']);" target="_blank">
					Download the 230 form</a>
			</div>
			<br />
			<p>If wages are not your exclusive income, fill in the 200 form.
			<a href="##app_root##/doneaza.aspx#formular200">details...</a></p>
			<div class="DownloadItem">
				<a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular200_2015_Neurocare.pdf" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 200', 'Coloana din dreapta']);" target="_blank">
					<img src="##app_root##/App/Images/PdfIcon.png" alt="Pdf Icon" /></a>
				<a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular200_2015_Neurocare.pdf" class="Text" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 200', 'Coloana din dreapta']);" target="_blank">
					Download the 200 form</a>
			</div>
			]]>
		</RightContent2>
	</Common>
  <Master PreviewUrl="~/">
    <Motto><![CDATA[Join us - for life!]]></Motto>
		<Menu1><![CDATA[Home]]></Menu1>
		<Menu2><![CDATA[Aim and objectives]]></Menu2>
		<Menu3><![CDATA[Life Stories]]></Menu3>
		<Menu4><![CDATA[Media]]></Menu4>
		<Menu5><![CDATA[Sponsors]]></Menu5>
		<Menu6><![CDATA[Donate]]></Menu6>
		<Menu7><![CDATA[Contact]]></Menu7>
		<Copyright><![CDATA[Copyright © 2010 Neurocare. All rights reserved.]]></Copyright>
	</Master>
  <Home PreviewUrl="~/">
		<HeadAbout><![CDATA[Who are we?]]></HeadAbout>
		<ContentAbout>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>We are doctors and nurses that live every day with the frustation of not being able to help our patients.
			We are the ones they look hopefully to and whom they ask for help. We are determined to change destinies!</p>
			]]>
		</ContentAbout>
		<HeadWishList><![CDATA[Wish list]]></HeadWishList>
		<HeadPartners><![CDATA[Partners]]></HeadPartners>
		<Content3Title1><![CDATA[Aspirator CUSA<br/>(Cavitron Ultrasonic Surgical Aspirator)]]></Content3Title1>
		<Content3Description1>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>
				CUSA este un aspirator ultrasonic care <b>taie, aspiră, coagulează</b> în acelaşi timp şi foarte important
				<b>respectă vasele.</b>
			</p><p>
				Dacă ne gândim că acest lucru "se întămplă" în creierul uman întelegeţi de ce este important să operezi curat şi cât mai precis,
				aici orice milimetru contează!
			</p>
			]]>
		</Content3Description1>
		<Content3Title2><![CDATA[Polisomnograf EEG digital NicOne&reg; <br />Wireless w32]]></Content3Title2>
		<Content3Description2>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>
				Sistemul <b>NicOne&reg;</b> Wireless w32 se diferenţiază de alte sisteme prin faptul că transmisia datelor culese de la pacient se face <b>wireless</b>.
				Acest lucru înseamnă că pacientul <b>nu va fi conectat la aparat prin fire</b> ci va purta fagurele într-o mică gentuţă la brâu sau la spate.
			</p><p>
				Avantajul	este major, copilul având libertate de mişcare fără a exista pericolul pierderii datelor achiziţionate, va putea să se deplaseze liber
				în timp ce datele culese de pe scalp sunt achiziţionate on-line, având o autonomie de deplasare de până la 250 m.
			</p><p>
				Astfel se pot realiza înregistrări de lungă durată, atât de zi cât şi de noapte fără a avea riscul de deterioare a aparatului în cazul unei crize.
			</p>
			]]>
		</Content3Description2>
		<Content3Title3><![CDATA[Sistem de Neuronavigatie<br /><br />]]></Content3Title3>
		<Content3Description3>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>
				Neuronavigaţia este <b>visul de aur</b> al oricărui neurochirurg, este <b>neurochirurgia 3D</b>! Acest sistem iţi permite să "navighezi" în creierul uman cu
				mare precizie, este o formă de chirurgie robotică. Astfel chiar şi leziunile mici şi profunde (greu de abordat cu microchirurgia clasică) se
				pot accesa şi trata.
			</p><p>
				<b>Neuronavigatia este GPS-ul pentru CREIER!</b>
			</p>
			]]>
		</Content3Description3>
		<Content3Title4><![CDATA[Resurse pentru specializarea<br />şi perfecţionarea medicilor tineri]]></Content3Title4>
		<Content3Description4>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>
				Nimeni nu se naşte învăţat aşa spune o veche vorbă românească.
			</p><p>
				Lucrăm alături de mulţi oameni tineri, frumoşi, dornici de a <b>profesa in România</b> de astăzi şi vrem să îi încurajăm să îi şcolim, să
				profesăm împreună cu ei o medicină de calitate. Avem oportunităţi de a ne perfecţiona dar... <b>nu avem resursele necesare</b>.
			</p>
			]]>
		</Content3Description4>
		<RightHead><![CDATA[Follow us on:]]></RightHead>
	</Home>
	<Contact>
		<Title><![CDATA[Contact]]></Title>
		<HeadLeft><![CDATA[Contact]]></HeadLeft>
		<ContentLeft>
			<![CDATA[
			<h3>Asociaţia Neurocare</h3>
			<p>Strada Clucerului Nr. 1, Sector 1, Bucureşti</p>
			<p><b>CUI:</b><br />
			27768141</p>

			<p><b>Account (IBAN):</b><br />
			RO21BRDE445SV26604894450<br />
			Account opened with BRD, Triumf Bucureşti branch</p>

			<p><b>Email:</b><br />
			<a href="mailto:office@neurocare.ro">office@neurocare.ro</a></p>
			<p><b>Telephone:</b><br />
			0724 726 756</p>
			]]>
		</ContentLeft>
		<HeadRight1><![CDATA[ACTIVE MEMBERS]]></HeadRight1>
		<ContentRight1>
			<![CDATA[
			<p><b>Dr. Raluca Teleanu</b> - Pediatric Neurology Physician.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Dan Teleanu</b> -	Neurosurgeon Physician.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Magda Sandu</b> - Pediatric Neurology Specialist.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Diana Epure</b> -	Pediatric Neurology Specialist.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Daniela Vasile</b> - Pediatric Neurology Specialist.</p>
			<p><b>As. Adina Istrate</b> - Chief Nurse of the Pediatric Neurology Ward.</p>
			]]>
		</ContentRight1>
		<HeadRight2><![CDATA[VOLUNTEERS]]></HeadRight2>
		<ContentRight2>
			<![CDATA[
			<p><b>Dr. Ana Maria Geanta</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Bogdan Buse</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Eugenia Roza</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Mihai Musetescu</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Oana Vladacenco</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			<p><b>Dr. Smaranda Nita</b> - Pediatric Neurology Resident.</p>
			]]>
		</ContentRight2>
	</Contact>
	<Cazuri>
		<Title><![CDATA[Life Stories]]></Title>
		<Head><![CDATA[Life Stories]]></Head>
		<Item1Title><![CDATA[Sorina's story]]></Item1Title>
		<Item2Title><![CDATA[Darius Preda]]></Item2Title>
		<Item3Title><![CDATA[Paying homage]]></Item3Title>
		<Item4Title><![CDATA[Sara's story]]></Item4Title>
		<Item5Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item5Title>
		<Item6Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item6Title>
		<Item1Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>It was a morning like any other; or at least it seemed so... From Dorohoi, via Bacău, a little girl came, carried in the arms of
			her mother. I came into the ward for the morning visit. The mother was standing next to the bed, and the child, scared of everything
			around her, couldn't walk, she had three paralysed limbs, and her eyes... Those eyes were watching me so fearfully, tears running
			down her cheeks!</p><br />

			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Sorina1.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>My first questions was: has the little girl always been like this? And the answer was 'no'. The child started to experience some
			dizziness, walking disorders, and then the impossibility to walk at all, at the same time when an alternating convergent strabismus
			appeared three months ago. In order to prove this, the mother showed me a video filmed on Sorina's birthday and I saw a beautiful
			little girl in a blue dress, running happily towards the place where she knew her friends and family were waiting for her. Almost a
			month later, something happened to Sorina. Something DIFFERENT.</p>
			<br />

			<p>It wasn't Sorina's first experience with a hospital: her destiny was being written six months after she was born, when she was very
			close to dying. She was diagnosed with infectious mononucleosis and the local newspapers presented her at the time as a desperate case
			with few chances to survive. She was in a coma. It was discovered that the little girl's bone marrow had a defect that prevented her
			from having a strong immune system.</p>
			<br />
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Sorina2.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>God had wanted her to live then, but by the time we met the situation was serious. After detailed investigations, we discovered
			that the whole central nervous system was affected, probably by a virus, and we couldn't tell how stable her condition was. But the
			trust of an amazing person, who hopefully supported and watched us, Sorina's mother, helped us find the solution needed to give the
			little girl her life back.</p>
			<br />

			<p>But the drama isn't gone even now, and it seems even more insidious: everything could start all over again! The hematologists that
			take care of Sorina test her periodically, in order to check the capability of the bone marrow... But can we know for sure?</p>
			<br />

			<p>What can we do for a child and a mother from Dorohoi, where people were flooded in the summer of 2010? They collected toys and
			cooked for the children with flooded houses! They could do something!</p>
			]]>
		</Item1Content>
		<Item1Author><![CDATA[Dr. Magda Sandu, December 2010]]></Item1Author>
		<Item2Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Darius1.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>Every time a child comes to our hospital, there are many things you notice during the first meeting... both from a human and from
			a medical point of view. Why has Darius touched my heart? Because his eyes smile all the time. Maybe just after his epileptic
			seizures a shadow covers his eyes for a short while. Even if every epileptic seizure usually means the erasing of all the progress
			obtained with a lot of effort, you can see in his eyes all the affection and hope this two-year-old child has to offer.</p>
			<br />

			<p>When he was 4 months old, Darius entered a status epilepticus in a village in Dâmboviţa. This means he had a seizure for more than
			15 minutes and his life could have ended then. He arrived in Bucharest, and in our hospital the investigations revealed that he had
			suffered a hemorrhagic stroke with right-side hemiparesis. Is it a genetic disorder, considering that one grandparent had a stroke
			when he was 4 years old? The investigations needed in order to trace this are very expensive.</p>
			<br />
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Darius2.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>In this hospital we have tried to throw as much light as possible on what the future could hold for Darius. But our wishes to help
			him always hit the same wall - it is too expensive to have a sick child. The price you pay with your heart is not enough. So we have
			to content ourselves with helping him not have other epileptic seizures (with three anticonvulsants) and with kinesiotherapy for his
			right hand and leg.</p>
			<br />

			<p>At the present his eyes are telling more than a thousand words could; he wants to walk (now possible just with orthopedic
			shoes - too expensive for his parents to buy in time), to play, to be healthy, to be at home.</p>
			<br />

			<p>For approximately two years, he and his mother have lived mostly in the hospital. We see him more often than his own family does.</p>
			]]>
		</Item2Content>
		<Item2Author><![CDATA[Dr. Magda Sandu, January 2011]]></Item2Author>
		<Item3Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<p>Every time I come home I ring the doorbell just once, thinking that maybe my son is asleep; but most of the times I hear him
			calling: <i>Bibi</i> (that's his nanny) <i>, mommy's home! I'll get the truck!</i> When I come in, he welcomes me as he's riding his
			toy-truck and starts to tell me quickly, skipping words, that he's done some things he shouldn't have... and he tells me everything
			hardly stopping to take a breath... he's two and a half years old.</p>
			<br />
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Exercitiu-de-admiratie1.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>I feel like crying and I say: <i>God, thank you!</i> And I start thinking of the mothers of George, Darius, or Cristina, or
			Ionela... (children who come in our hospital) and I can't stop asking myself: why aren't they as lucky as me? Why do children have
			to be sick? What divine purpose could a child's suffering have?</p>
			<br />

			<p>I may never come to understand that, but while searching for an answer, I can try to learn how to be a mother... from them! What
			I am about to write now is a humble homage for some women who never cease to amaze me. I can see the hope in their eyes, everytime
			we meet, waiting for a sign that the future will be different than the present. How many times have they imagined their children
			going to kindergarden or to their first day at school, at a school play reciting poems or blowing the candles on their birthday
			cake? How many times have they watched their children sleeping and thought the reality was not real? Questions hurt their hearts;
			they ask me these questions sometimes, but I know they don't expect me to give them a credible answer... maybe just a comforting
			word, a sign that someone understands what it means to forget yourself as a being, as a woman, and become just this: Mother.</p>
			<br />
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Exercitiu-de-admiratie2.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>If you, who are accidentally reading these lines, if you think you can define "sacrifice", think again! Could you completely
			forget yourselves as human beings, disregarding EVERYTHING ELSE except a smile, the holding of your hand, a timid step your child
			took? Everytime I speak with the mothers of these children, I feel there are so many things I want to ask them! I would listen to
			them and I would watch them for hours, hugging their beloved angels. I say angels because I'm thinking of George, whose illness
			prevents him, a 4-year old boy, from hugging his mother; or even from calling her when he needs her. But he doesn't have to, because
			She's always there for him... He is spirit more than anything... When he was almost three years old, he learned how to smile to
			his mother.</p>
			<br />
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Exercitiu-de-admiratie3.jpg" class="Content" alt="" />

			<p>I'm thinking of Ileana Ispas and of Ionela Agavriloaie, for which the year should have 365 Mother's Days and it still wouldn't be
			enough. Of Alexandru Nuţă's mother, who smiles at me every morning when I come into the ward, although her son has daily seizures.
			She smiles so he can see her smiling and not crying, while she soothes him. So he can keep going.</p>
			<br />

			<p>For all these and for every lesson they are teaching me, I thank them! In a false and shallow world, they make me feel as if I
			hold a beating heart in my hand, and their feelings become my feelings. Can I ever repay them for that?</p>
			]]>
		</Item3Content>
		<Item3Author><![CDATA[Dr. Magda Sandu, March 2011]]></Item3Author>
		<Item4Content>
		<![CDATA[
		<p>Sara, a 4-month old baby girl who has never looked into her mother's eyes ... for her mother went to Heaven much too soon, giving birth to her.</p>
		<br />

		<p>I met her a month ago, when she was brought to the clinic - she had severe neurological disorders following an extremely difficult labour;
		deprived of her mother's affection and breast feeding, she couldn't even drink her milk by herself - this had to be administered via a
		feeding tube directly into her stomach.</p>

		<p>She was accompanied by her grandmother, an extraordinary woman with an unbelievable psychological strength. Although she had gone through a
		horrible ordeal when recently losing her daughter, she offered her granddaughter all the necessary support to help her cope - she was always
		by her side, feeding her through the tube, changing her, rocking her, trying to comfort her every minute. And it wasn't easy, as the baby girl
		was agitated, had trouble breathing, and had numerous daily seizures.</p>
		<br />

		<p>For a month we tried to stop her seizures. Both her age and her low weight didn't allow us to use a varied range of anticonvulsants.</p>

		<p>The baby girl's two grandmothers didn't sleep for days in a row, taking turns in looking after Sara. By day they watched us fight with the
		seizures, with the breathing and feeding disorders, and by night they tried to comfort the agitated little girl who didn't sleep at all.</p>

		<p>It is difficult to watch a newborn that always sleeps stiffly, with tense fists, as if she is incessantly fighting for her life.</p>
		<br />

		<p>But God helped us and after numerous attempts the seizures became rarer and we tried to remover her feeding tube and use the baby bottle to
		give her the milk. It wasn't possible, because Sara didn't know how to suck or to swallow. But we didn't give up. Patiently, our nurses managed
		to give her the milk with a syringe - her first meal administed like this lasted an hour...</p>
		<br />

		<p>I couldn't imagine until then the joy of seeing that a patient has received her milk through a syringe or a special baby bottle for three days.
		And the image of Sara sleeping relaxed for the first time, with her tiny hands opened, like a little angel, is still with me day and night.</p>
		<br />

		<p>Although I know we are still fighting so that this baby girl with the face of an angel recovers after the trauma of her birth, I trust in God
		that these small steps are leading towards a better medical condition of our little patient.</p>

		<p>And I can't stop praying that my three-year old son continues to be healthy, as the baby that I'm looking forward to see for the first time
		in less than 2 months, and that I should be able to offer my children everything they will need.</p>
		]]>
		</Item4Content>
		<Item4Author><![CDATA[Dr. Diana Epure, November 2011]]></Item4Author>
		<Item5Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item5Content>
		<Item5Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item5Author>
		<Item6Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item6Content>
		<Item6Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item6Author>
		<RightHead1><![CDATA[Sorina's story]]></RightHead1>
		<RightContent1>
			<![CDATA[
			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Sorina2.jpg" class="Feature" />
			<p>It was a morning like any other; or at least it seemed so... From Dorohoi, via Bacău, a little girl came, carried in the arms of
			her mother. I came into the ward for the morning visit. The mother was standing next to the bed, and the child, scared of everything
			around her, couldn't walk, she had three paralysed limbs, and her eyes...
			<a href="##app_root##/cazuri/povestea-sorinei.aspx" runat="server">read more</a></p>
			]]>
		</RightContent1>
	</Cazuri>
	<Presa>
		<TitlePrefix><![CDATA[Neurocare Association - Media - ]]></TitlePrefix>
		<Title><![CDATA[Media]]></Title>
		<Head><![CDATA[Media]]></Head>
		<Item1Title><![CDATA[Ski instructor cured by Dr. Dan Teleanu]]></Item1Title>
		<Item1Head><![CDATA[Vali Căciulă is getting better!]]></Item1Head>
		<Item2Title><![CDATA[The man who beat four cancer types in a year]]></Item2Title>
		<Item2Head><![CDATA[The man who beat four cancer types in a year]]></Item2Head>
		<Item3Title><![CDATA[Dr. Dan Teleanu  in "Doctor, you are my hero!"]]></Item3Title>
		<Item3Head><![CDATA[Doctor Dan Teleanu, the neurosurgeon who understood that cutting edge technology isn't everything]]></Item3Head>
		<Item4Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item4Title>
		<Item4Head><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item4Head>
		<Item5Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item5Title>
		<Item5Head><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item5Head>
		<Item6Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item6Title>
		<Item6Head><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item6Head>
		<Item7Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item7Title>
		<Item7Head><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item7Head>
		<Item8Title><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item8Title>
		<Item8Head><![CDATA[We are sorry! This page is not available in English.]]></Item8Head>
		<Item1Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<h3>The medical condition of Vali Căciulă, the most famous ski instructor in Romania, is continously improving.</h3>

			<p>Better and better news for those who know Vali Căciulă. After two brain surgeries, the ski instructor from Sinaia feels better
			every day. <i>"His health is continously improving. He started to eat. I'm optimistic!"</i>, says Codruţ Căciulă, the son of the
			great ski instructor.</p>

			<p>His optimism is shared by the doctor <b>Dan Teleanu</b>, who operated on Căciulă Senior at the Neuorosurgery department of
			Spitalul Universitar (University Hospital) from Bucharest. <i>"Now he feels better. He goes to the bathroom and eats by himself,
			he talks... He made great progress, even if he still has problems from time to time. On Friday or Monday we could release him"</i>,
			declared the doctor who picked up Vali Căciulă from the snow and put him back on the skis.</p>

			<p>After this, the ski instructor has to follow a very strict recovery programme. The costs of this process are very high, so anyone
			who wants to help him can do this by donating money to the accounts: RO82INGB0000999900635852 - for lei and for euro -
			RO39INGB0000999901661043 opened with ING Bank. The accounts are opened under the name Căciulă Constantin Codruţ.</p>
			]]>
		</Item1Content>
		<Item1Author>
			<![CDATA[
			Source: schiromania.ro, 23 February 2011<br />
			<a href="http://www.schiromania.ro/2011/02/23/vali-caciula-isi-revine/" target="_blank">http://www.schiromania.ro/2011/02/23/vali-caciula-isi-revine/</a>
			]]>
		</Item1Author>
		<Item2Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<h3>The last obstacle was overcome two weeks ago, when his brain tumor was removed.</h3>

			<img src="##app_root##/Images/Presa/Articol1.jpg" class="General" align="middle" width="425" height="262"><br />
			<p class="Author">Photo: Silviu Ciobanu</p>

			<p>Thin and with a bandaged head, Florin quickly gets out of bed when he sees me coming into the ward. His wife is by his side and
			this makes it easier for him to deal with his problems. Until last year he hadn't had any health issues. In April 2010 he went to a
			private clinic in Galati to have a swelling mass removed - it was as big as a bean and it had appeared on his armpit. While he was
			waiting for the biopsy results, he experienced a terrible headache one night. In a short time, the 42-year-old man would find out
			that he suffered from melanoma, brain tumor and lung metastasis. <i>"The doctors said at the time that the brain tumors are
			inoperable. I underwent chemotherapy and cobalt therapy and, after a few months, a part of them disappeared completely. After the
			treatment, the lung metastasis disappeared as well"</i>, says Florian. In December last year Florian found out that he also had
			small intestine metastasis. He felt nauseous, he couldn't keep the food down, and he had pains which would pass only with Metamizole.
			After surgery these disappeared as well.</p>

			<h3>The brain surgery lasted four hours</h3>

			<p>Florian came to Spitalul Universitar (University Hospital) in Bucharest two weeks ago to see what could be done about the brain
			tumor. The doctor said it could be operated on. <i>"The surgery lasted four hours and it implied removing the brain metastasis. It
			is a complex procedure, with bleeding risks, and we had to be very careful not to touch brain structures that would leave the patient
			with a neurological postop deficit"</i>, as Dan Teleanu, neurosurgeon at the Spitalul Universitar (University Hospital) in Bucharest,
			explains. He also says that, in Florin's case, the survival chances depend on how well the melanoma is controled. Florian is not
			allowed to drink coffee or alcohol anymore, and he mustn't expose his head to the sun. Otherwise he risks having epileptic seizures.</p>

			<h3>"These tragedies happen when you least expect them to"</h3>

			<p>A chaotic lifestyle, an unhealthy diet and pollution cause brain tumors to appear even with people who are 30-40 years old. In some
			cases, the tumors can have secondary origins, as in Florian's case. For example, a woman who had breast cancer or a man with lung cancer
			present the risk of brain metastasis as well. Tumors can also appear without a well-known cause. <i>"Benign brain tumors can appear
			with women with multiple pregnancies due to hormonal issues or with patients who are 60-70 years old"</i>, says Dan Teleanu.</p>

			<p>The most dangerous form of brain cancer, glioblastoma, is more frequent in men, and the survival rate is of 8 months. Headaches,
			epileptic seizures, sight disorders, paresis on the side of the tumor and an eyesight deficit are the signs of a brain tumor. To catch
			the disease eraly, the doctors recommend a neurological consult once a year after the age of 35. <i>"These tragedies happen when you
			least expect them to. I had been very happy before I found out I was sick. Now I want to live until I am at least 50 years old, to get
			well, to go to work and to take care of my 10-year-old daughter"</i>, says Florian, who can't find an explanation why he got sick.
			<i>"I only drank alcohol occasionally and I haven't touched a cigarette since 1995. I have always done exercise. I just ate a lot of
			sweets, because I have a sweet tooth. Maybe I got sick for having stayed in the sun too much. I have enjoyed swimming since I was a kid,
			and then I worked on a ship in the sun all my life"</i>, he says as he tries to find an answer.</p>

			<p><i>"The surgery to remove the brain metastasis has bleeding risks, and we have to be very careful not to touch brain structures that
			would leave the patient with a neurological postop deficit"</i><br />
			<b>DAN TELEANU</b>, neurosurgeon</p>
			]]>
		</Item2Content>
		<Item2Author>
			<![CDATA[
			Source: romanialibera.ro, 15 March 2011<br />
			<a href="http://www.romanialibera.ro/stil-de-viata/sanatate/barbatul-care-a-invins-patru-forme-de-cancer-intr-un-an-219465.html" target="_blank">
			http://www.romanialibera.ro/stil-de-viata/sanatate/barbatul-care-a-invins-patru-forme-de-cancer-intr-un-an-219465.html</a>]]></Item2Author>
		<Item3Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<iframe src='http://www.stirileprotv.ro/lbin/video_embed.php?media_id=60529786&section=20330&video_section_id=' frameborder='0' style='width: 400px; height: 330px;' scrolling="no"></iframe>

			<br /><br />
			<h3>For 15 years, a kind giant has been healing a part of our body specialists declare they know too little about - the human brain.</h3>

			<br />
			<p>There are interventions few know how to do, and even fewer have the courage to tackle them.</p>

			<p>When he attended university, brain surgery was pure avant-gardism. Since then, Dan Teleanu has seen and treated hundreds of tumors.</p>

			<p>He's 44 years old, and he is seen as a rare example of kindness by those whose future hangs by a thread. That is, by the biopsy that
			will give them a verdict - was it malignant or not? During a few months spent in Germany, the doctor understood that cutting edge
			technology isn't everything.</p>

			<p>This was confirmed with Cornel, a 28-year-old patient who lived with a simple headache. In pictures, the brain issue was not easily
			detected. The young man thinks he was lucky.</p>

			<p>Another patient operated on by Teleanu and cured, in just a year, of four cancer types, would say that he met a gifted man.</p>

			<p>He has two children, whom he sees less than he would like and than they would all deserve.</p>

			<p>But it is still his wife, a pediatric neurologist, that he asks for help with his patients who are children.</p>
			]]>
		</Item3Content>
		<Item3Author>
			<![CDATA[
			Source: stirileprotv.ro, 23 November 2011<br />
			<a href="http://stirileprotv.ro/stiri/11-septembrie/campanie-doctori.html" target="_blank">
			http://stirileprotv.ro/stiri/11-septembrie/campanie-doctori.html</a>]]></Item3Author>
		<Item4Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item4Content>
		<Item4Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item4Author>
		<Item5Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item5Content>
		<Item5Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item5Author>
		<Item6Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item6Content>
		<Item6Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item6Author>
		<Item7Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item7Content>
		<Item7Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item7Author>
		<Item8Content><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item8Content>
		<Item8Author><![CDATA[&nbsp;]]></Item8Author>
	</Presa>
	<Doneaza>
		<Title><![CDATA[Donate]]></Title>
		<Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<h2 class="NoPadding">YOU CAN MAKE A CASH DONATION!</h2>
			<i>(for natural persons)</i><br /><br />

			<p>Donate periodically or occasionally an amount of money for the cause you choose.</p>
			<p>The donations will be used to help the vulnerable people who turn to us. We are extremely grateful! Without your financial help, many material
			support activities of the patients could not have happened.</p>

			<h3>How can you donate?</h3>

			<p>- By contacting us at 0724 726 756<br />
			- By bank transfer into the account of the Neurocare Association<br />
				&nbsp;&nbsp;Account in Lei: RO21BRDE445SV26604894450 (account opened with BRD, Triumf Bucureşti branch)</p>
		
			<br /><br />
			<h2 class="NoPadding">YOU CAN SPONSOR US!</h2>
			<i>(for legal persons)</i><br /><br />

			<h3 class="NoPadding">If you are the decision maker in a company, sponsor one of the actions of the association, and the amount can be
			deducted from your taxes.</h3>
			<p>A part of the projects carried out by the Neurocare Association benefit from the financial support offered by some legal persons from
			Romania. We greatly appreciate their social commitment! Your company can also support our patients to start a new life!</p>

			<h3>Who can sponsor?</h3>
			<p>Any economic entity with a profit can choose that a part of the profit tax due to the state is sent to a NGO. In case of tax payers that
			are legal persons, that is economic entities, there are a series of deductible expenses. Even if the deductibility of these expenses does
			not represent a real financial stimulant, it can help when taking the decision of supporting a non-governmental organization.</p>

			<h3>How high is the amount that can be deducted?</h3>
			<p>Sign a sponsorship contract with the Neurocare Association and you can deduct 20% from the profit tax due to the state, in the limit of
			3% of the company's turnover (article 31 paragraph 4 from the Law 571/2003 regarding Fiscal practice). Basically this means that you will
			pay the tax minus the value of your sponsorhips in that year.</p>

			<h3>What is the legal status?</h3>
			<p>Sponsorship represents a juridical agreement through which two entities concur regarding the transfer of property rights for some material
			goods or financial means in order to support several activities without a lucrative aim carried out by one of the parties, called the
			beneficiary of the sponsorship. According to law 32/1994 regarding sponsorship, further amendments included, the sponsorship is implemented
			with a written contract signed by the sponsor and the beneficiary. which specifies the object, the value and the duration of the sponsorship,
			as well as the rights and the obligations of the parties.<br />
			In the case of a sponsorship that consists of material goods, these will be evaluated within a signed juridical document at their real value
			at the moment they are consigned to the beneficiary.</p>
			<p>Any company has the right to offer sponsorships above the limits mentioned as well, but for the amount that surpasses the indicated limit
			the company will pay the profit tax.<br />
			The sponsorship must be registered with accounting the year for which the tax is paid (the year previous to the real payment). The provisions
			of article 31 paragraph 4 from the Law 571/2003 regarding the Fiscal Code apply to all profit tax payers, regardless if their incomes
			originate from Romania or from abroad.<br />
			There are also deductible the advertising expenses undergone with the purpose of raising awareness for the company or products based on a
			written contract. This category includes promotional goods and service. (article 21.(2) d) of Law 571/2003 regarding the Fiscal Code).<br />
			Thus one can include in the category of advertising expenses, and therefore deductible, activties such as supporting a NGO event with a large
			number of participants (competitions, openings, concerts, 1st of June or Christmas events etc). One can also include here product donations
			as the advertising category also covers the goods and services offered for free as samples. In the same context can be included the support
			given for some NGOs' publications, as long as these display the sponsor's name/logo/message.</p>

			<h3>What do you need to do?</h3>
			<p>The sponsorship procedure is very simple. It consists of signing a sponsorship contract between the company and the Neurocare Association,
			based on which the money can be deducted from the profit tax. Transfer the amount in the account of the Neurocare Association and specify the
			activity you want to support. Once your money is used, you will receive a report on what it was spent and the impact it had on our patients' lives.</p>

			<h3>What are your advantages as an employer?</h3>
			<p>You can control a part of the money due to the state.<br />
			The name of the company you manage will appear in the Annual Report of the Neurocare Association, which is made public on the web page.<br />
			This sponsorship is a means to motivate the employees, who can thus feel that the company they work for is socially responsible and committed.</p>
			<p>If you wish to sponsor an activity of our association or you need more information regarding sponsorships, feel free to contact us. We would
			be honoured to have you by our side! Thank you!</p>
		
			<br /><br />
			<h2 class="NoPadding">YOU CAN DIRECT 2% OF THE INCOME TAX!</h2>
			<i>(for natural persons)</i><br /><br />

			<h3>Direct 2% of the taxes you pay to the state in order to finance the programmes of the association.</h3>
			<h3>What does 2% represent?</h3>
			<p>Tax payers who are natural persons can decide on the destination of an amount representing up to 2% of the annual income tax owed to
			the state, as per article 57 paragraph (4) and article 84 paragraph (2) of the Governmental Emergency Decree no. 138/2004 for modifying
			and completing the Law regarding the Fiscal code no. 571/2003 and enforced by Law no. 163/2005. Thus natural persons can sponsor
			non-profit entities that run according to Government Decree 26/2000 for associations and foundations.</p>

			<h3>Choose how to use 2% of your tax!</h3>
			<p>You can directly decide what happens with the taxes you pay by directing 2% to a non-governmental organization.<br />
			This costs you nothing. You can be involved without any additional costs in supporting important social causes.<br />
			You just need to fill in and file a fiscal form by the 15th of May 2011. If you do not use this option, this percentage will be cashed
			in and managed by the state.</p>

			<h3>What isn't the 2%?</h3>
			<p>Directing 2% of your income tax is not a donation or a sponsorship!<br />
			It is about an amount of money owed to the state (as taxes), but you can decide how and by whom it will be spent.<br />
			2% does NOT mean additional costs for the tax payer, but a part of what the state already charges. In other words, instead of taking 100%,
			the state will receive from you just 98% and the rest of 2% will be directed where you choose to.<br />
			Directing 2% is not a legal method of fiscal fraud! You do not have the right to ask the organization you direct 2% to for any financial
			or other benefits.</p>

			<h3>Why should you direct 2% to the Neurocare Association?</h3>
			<p>You can thus help the patients and us to offer quality medical support and you can decide how your taxes are spent. Directing 2% is
			not mandatory, it is an option that contributes to the efficiency of managing public expenses.<br />
			No state authority, organization or employer can force you to do this.<br />
			As a non-profit organization, our resources are limited, and the majority of our activities are carried out due to sponsorships and donations.</p>

			<h3>How can you direct 2% to the Neurocare Association?</h3>
			<p>The global income statement is filed with the Administration of Public Finances (from the town where your residence on the ID card is)
			personally or by mail.<br />
			The addresses of the financial administrations are available on the ANAF site.</p>
			<p><b>Attention!</b><br />
			If you don't know the exact amount represented by the 2%, don't fill in the box. The fiscal authorities must calculate and fill it in accordingly.</p>
 
			<p><b><a name="formular230" class="Anchor">If you are an employee with a working contract or you work for the public administration, or if you
			received an income similar to salaries (administrator stipend, director or associates stipend, the net profit amount owed to administrators in
			national companies, the stipend a building manager gets) etc:</a></b></p>
			<p>- Download from here <a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular230_2015_Neurocare.pdf" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 230', 'Pagina doneaza']);" target="_blank">Form 230</a>
			"Request regarding the destination of the amount up to 2% of the annual income tax and deducting the expenses made for the collective saving in the
			housing field" .pdf (can also be obtained for free from any financial administration).<br />
			- Print the form (1 page) in two copies.</p>

			<p>The form is to be filled out with the data requested in capital letters, legibly and correctly.<br />
			Complete both copies as it follows:</p>
			<p>Year: 2010<br />
			I. TAX PAYER IDENTIFICATION DATA: surname, father's name initial, first name, CNP (personal numerical code), residence address.</p>
			<p>II. DESTINATION OF THE AMOUNT REPRESENTING UP TO 2% FROM THE ANNUAL TAX AS PER ARTICLE 57 PARAGRAPH (4) OF LAW NO. 571/2003, tick the
			corresponding box:<br />
			(1. Private scholarship: don't tick and don't fill in/cross it out).<br />
			2. Supporting a non-profit/ religious entity: the amount - fill in the donated amount or don't fill in anything, if you don't know the amount
			that can be transfered; the fiscal authority will calculate and transfer the amount as per law. The full name of the non-profit/ religious entity.
			Fiscal identification code of the non-profit/ religious entity. Bank account (IBAN) of the non-profit/ religious entity</p>
			<p>III. Don't fill it it / cross it out.<br />
			- Sign.<br />
			- For the income obtained in the year 2010, the form for redirecting 2% of the income tax is filled in in two copies; one is filed with the fiscal
			authority within the range of which you have the legal or actual residence address, if the latter is different from the legal one (for natural
			persons who have fiscal residence in Romania), or with the fiscal authority within the range of which the income source resides, for the other
			tax payers as natural persons.<br />
			- The forms are filed by the 15th of May 2011 directly with the registry of the fiscal authority, by mail (registered letter) or at our offices,
			and we will file it for you with the Fiscal administration.<br />
			- A copy will be kept by you.</p>

			<p><b><a name="formular200" class="Anchor">If you obtained in the year 2010 incomes from other sources</b> (registered sole trader real system,
			registered sole trader income norms, liberal professions - doctor, lawyer, notary, chartered accountant, architect, rent, investments earnings,
			copyright, agricultural activities etc), you have the legal obligation (except registered sole trader income norms) to file with the financial
			administration a statement regarding the income you made the previous year - form 200. With the same form, under a separate heading, you can
			donate 2% of the due taxes (more details at: <a href="http://declaratia200.ro/" target="_blank">http://declaratia200.ro/</a>):</p>
			<p>- Download from here <a href="##app_root##/Files/Formular200_2015_Neurocare.pdf" onclick="_gaq.push(['_trackEvent', 'Downloads', 'Formular 200', 'Pagina doneaza']);" target="_blank">Form 200</a>
			"Obtained income statement" .pdf (can also be obtained for free from any financial administration).<br />
			- Print the form (5 pages) in 2 copies.</p>
			<p>The form is to be filled out with the data requested in capital letters, legibly and correctly.<br />
			Complete both copies as it follows:</p>
			<p>Year: 2010<br />
			I. TAX PAYER IDENTIFICATION DATA: surname, father's name initial, first name, CNP (personal numerical code), residence address.</p>
			<p>II. DATA REGRADING THE INCOME OBTAINED FROM SOURCES AND INCOME CATEGORIES: it will be filled in with information regarding the
			income obtained the previous year as per instructions.</p>
			<p>III. DESTINATION OF THE AMOUNT REPRESENTING 2% FROM THE TAX DUE FOR THE TAXABLE ANNUAL NET INCOME/ ANNUAL NET EARNINGS, tick the corresponding box:<br />
			(1. Private scholarship: don't tick and don't fill in/cross it out).<br />
			2. Supporting a non-profit/ religious entity: the amount - fill in the donated amount or don't fill in anything, if you don't know the amount
			that can be transfered; the fiscal authority will calculate and transfer the amount as per law. The full name of the non-profit/ religious entity.
			Fiscal identification code of the non-profit/ religious entity. Bank account (IBAN) of the non-profit/ religious entity.</p>
			<p>IV. Don't fill it it / cross it out/ fill it in only if a fiscal representative nominated by the tax payer carries out the obligation of
			declaring the income.<br />
			- Enclose documents that prove the obtained income.<br />
			- Sign.<br />
			- For the income obtained in the year 2010, the form for redirecting 2% of the income tax is filled in in two copies; one is filed with the
			fiscal authority within the range of which you have the legal or actual residence address, if the latter is different from the legal one
			(for natural persons who have fiscal residence in Romania), or with the fiscal authority within the range of which the income source resides,
			for the other tax payers as natural persons.<br />
			- The forms are filed by the 15th of May 2011 directly with the registry of the fiscal authority, by mail (registered letter) or at our
			offices, and we will file it for you with the Fiscal administration.<br />
			- A copy will be kept by you.</p>
 
			<p><b>If you obtained your income both from salaries and from other sources</b>, fill in and file both forms 230 and 200 at the latest by
			the 15th of May 2011.</p>
 
			<h3>What are our data?</h3>
			<p>Non-profit entity name: Asociaţia Neurocare<br />
			Fiscal identification code of the non-profit entity: 27768141<br />
			Bank account (IBAN) of the non-profit entity: RO21BRDE445SV26604894450 (account opened with BRD, Triumf Bucureşti branch)</p>
 
			<p>Please fill in carefully all the data, including the data of the organization: name, fiscal code and bank account.<br />
			Atenttion! The bank account in the IBAN format has 24 digits!</p>
 
			<p>For more information regarding our activties, please feel free to contact us!<br />
			honoured to have you by our side! Thank you!</p>
			]]>
		</Content>
	</Doneaza>
	<Scop>
		<Title><![CDATA[Aim and objectives]]></Title>
		<Head><![CDATA[Aim and objectives]]></Head>
		<Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<ul>
				<li>Attracting material and financial funds in order to finance the activity carried out by the association doctors in the neurology/neurosurgery wards in hospitals;</li>
				<li>Attracting material and financial funds in order to finance the activity of the institutions and of the organizations that take on the people with neurological/ neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Attracting material and financial funds in order to finance the activity of the cultural and sport institutions and organizations for the projects aimed at people with neurological/ neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Creating and financing modern medical facilities for the diagnosis, treatment and research of the neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Creating and financing rehabilitation facilities for people with neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Organizing lucrative activities for the people with neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Organizing courses to train the specialists, social workers and volunteers who work with neurological/ neurosurgical disorders, as well as the caregivers of the people with neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Organizing activities that will raise awareness in the civil society and will influence its members' mentality towards people with neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Ensuring management of several nongovernmental organizations and associations from the social, educational, cultural and sport fields, for projects related to people with neurological/neurosurgical disorders;</li>
				<li>Organising symposiums, round tables, meetings and contacts among the Romanian and foreign specialists;</li>
				<li>Translating, editing, printing and publishing books, magazines, CDs and other specialized audio-visual materials in order to support the activities of the association;</li>
				<li>Creating a reference library for the use of the specialists or of any person working in the neurology/neurosurgery field;</li>
				<li>Creating funds aimed at granting study scholarships for emerging specialists;</li>
				<li>Maintaining partnerships with other foundations, organizations and associations from Romania or abroad.</li>
			</ul>
			]]>
		</Content>
	</Scop>
	<Sponsori>
		<Title><![CDATA[Sponsors]]></Title>
		<Head><![CDATA[Sponsors]]></Head>
		<Content>
			<![CDATA[
			<ul>
				<li><a href="http://zenyth.ro/" target="_blank">Zenyth Pharmaceuticals</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://asociatia.drumulpotcoavei.ro/" target="_blank">Zona Drumul Potcoavei Association</a></li>
				<li>The family Corina and Florin Mălureanu</li>
				<li>Adela Chirică</li>
				<li>Nicolae Sota</li>
				<li><a href="http://www.elaptepraf.ro" target="_blank">Elaptepraf.ro (powdered milk)</a></li>
				<li><a href="http://www.romegacontrol.ro" target="_blank">Ro-Mega Control</a></li>
				<li>Adriana Stere</li>
				<li>Daniel Angelescu</li>
				<li>Ionela Iordachi</li>
				<li><a href="http://www.intesasanpaolobank.ro/" target="_blank">Intesa Sanpaolo Bank</a></li>
				<li>The family Oana and Sorin Trâmbiţaş</li>
				<li>The family Daria and Ovidiu Mihet</li>
				<li>The family Monica and Ionut Jilaveanu</li>
				<li>Alex Dima</li>
				<li>Enache Oana</li>
				<li>Dubau Ana</li>
			</ul>
			]]>
		</Content>
	</Sponsori>
</translations>